Ravens fans, I'm so excited to sit down
with the newest member of the team,
first-round pick Vanga Yawane. Vanga,
congratulations. Welcome to Baltimore.
>> Thank you so much. I appreciate it. So,
you walk in this building and you are
officially a Raven. You have the Ravens
hat on right now. What are the emotions
as you come to the reality that you are
a member of this team? I'm happy. I'm
excited. There's a lot of feelings that
go into it, but the biggest thing for me
is being excited to be here. Got to be
happy. Something that stood out to me in
hearing from you after you were picked
and from the Ravens is that when you
came here for your visit, it sounded
like everybody felt like this is a match
made in heaven. Take me back to that
day. What were your thoughts when you
were here and when you left this
building? [music]
When I left, it was definitely a good
feeling. Um for me as I went through the
entire building, met a lot of people.
Biggest thing that stood out to me was
that it was a family. You know, it
wasn't a It wasn't a job interview or
anything like that. Everybody made me
feel comfortable. Uh everybody here was
just good people. You know, I had a good
time. Just had normal conversation with
everybody I met with, so. And and as you
go through this draft process, you meet
with so many people, so many teams. What
was it that made it feel like this is a
family atmosphere, a place that I could
really see myself? Um the meeting that I
had with Jamison to start off. You know,
we just sat in there and just talked.
You know, that's all it was. You know, I
love when people can just have, you
know, normal conversations, things like
that, so. But knowing that this place
is, you know, history. There's a lot of,
you know, legends that came through
here, a lot of good people that came
through here, so. I'm excited for that.
Part of the family atmosphere, I'm sure,
is the connection that you've already
started to build with your offensive
line coach Dwayne Ledford. And we got a
taste of that last night when he got on
the call to welcome you to Baltimore.
Yes, sir. What was it like when he got
on that phone call last night? Hey,
WHAT'S UP, BIG DOG? YEAH, YEAH, what's
up, man? I was really excited, man. You
know, I was a little, you know, little
emotional going through it, but as soon
as he got on, he got me hyped, so that's
how it was. And what has the process
been like getting to know him? It's been
real cool. Uh he was at my pro day. You
know, he held the bag for me as I went
and I was showing, you know, putting him
on a little bit. That's how it was, but
he's a good guy. You uh will have a
chance to block for Lamar Jackson, one
of the best, if not the very best player
in the NFL. What are your thoughts about
the responsibility and the opportunity
that that presents? Yeah, for me, when I
get here, the biggest thing is, you
know, earning the right to block for
him, you know, and all the other guys.
You know, I got to earn my keep, but
knowing that I got a quarterback like
that, it's going to make my job easier.
Now, something that stands out to me,
and everyone has said this, is your
mentality. And we've got a taste of it
uh since since drafting you, just some
of the things that you've said and
you've talked about. Nobody touches my
quarterback.
>> Nobody's going to touch my quarterback,
man. Simple as that. Nobody's going to
stand in front of me and survive. That's
my biggest mentality.
>> the mentality that you have, the switch
that you flip when you get on that
field.
Where does that come from?
>> Yeah, playing the game of football as an
O-lineman, you're always going to have
that mentality, you know. You got to
come in thinking that you have to be the
best player on the field. You know,
you're playing O-line, but you're
playing with four other guys that got to
be playing as one. You know, with the
guy behind you that we got to protect,
you got to have the mentality of
nobody's going to touch him. That's
That's it for me. You know, not every
offensive lineman has highlights, but
you've got some highlights, okay? And I
want to share some with you here. I want
you to run through a couple of these
plays here because I think this speaks
to the mentality that we're talking
about here. So, I got two plays here and
you can start it. Take me through this
play, and you know this one probably
right off the bat.
>> Yes, sir.
Yeah, man, uh our OC, you know, put a
lot of trust in me, you know, coming in
motion playing
H on the slot, you know, but
biggest thing for me is going into the
week knowing exactly what I was supposed
to do.
>> [music]
>> Coming down, I'm just trying to kill
somebody. Knowing it's a it's a free
shot to, you know, just hurt somebody,
play physical football, and that's
exactly what it was.
>> When you get out in space like that, I
mean, that's an opportunity that Is that
an offensive lineman's dream when you're
moving full steam ahead like that?
Absolutely. It's something you want to
do as a as an O-lineman.
>> [music]
>> I mean, you know, you could add a
little, you know, fake, get out there on
the flat, get the ball, but, you know,
we'll see how that works out.
And then the other one here is uh here
we go.
The same play, line up outside, but
instead of, you know, killing the D-end,
just faking him out and then getting out
in space and blocking that corner for
the quarterback. You know, didn't work
out, but, you know, just having that
trust in me to get out there and block a
fast corner, that's that means a lot to
me. I don't see offensive linemen
putting fakes too often on tape, but you
did it on that play. Is that Talk me
Tell me about that a little bit. Biggest
thing is you got to be athletic and have
trust in yourself to do something like
that. You know, you're running full
speed and in a tight space, you got to
be able to, you know, take a little jab
step and then get out, so. And then one
other thing I want to ask you about is,
you know, there's this mentality, this
tenacity that we're talking about, but
there's also this humility. There was
the clip as as you've seen many times of
you helping the equipment guy push the
cart up up the ramp.
Talk to me about this humility side, you
know, not the mentality, the nastiness
that you play with on the field, but
that aspect of things as well.
I mean, it's as simple as how I grew up.
You know, my parents uh you know, taught
me a lot of things,
but that video, you know, going around,
whatever, is cool, but it was nothing
more than just helping out somebody who
needed help. You know, it's nothing more
than that, so. And lastly, when you get
on the field this year for the Ravens,
what do you want to do? What do you want
to accomplish? For me, when I come in,
you know, I understand how the game of
football works. Nobody wants to hear
from a rookie. They want to see, you
know, what they can do, how they can
earn their keep, things like that, so.
That's my entire mentality coming in.
Awesome. Well, we can't wait to see you
on that field. See you get to work.
Appreciate it.
>> Appreciate y'all.